

Omar Reda
Front-End Developer

# **CONTACT**

+201094407154

omarmreda95@gmail.com

Cairo, Egypt

linkedin.com/in/omarmreda

SASS

github.com/omarmreda

# **SKILLS**

HTML

000

CSS • Bootstrap

JavaScript • npm

React.js • Git

Redux • Angular

### **LANGUAGES**

**English** Fluent

Arabic Native

French Beginner

#### SUMMARY

Architect Engineer with 2+ years experience in fast track projects. Looking forward to leverage my design skills and my passion about programming to build user interfaces of web applications and using my programming knowledge to code websites' appearance.

### **EDUCATION**

## The British University in Egypt

2013 -2018

Bachelor of Engineering – Faculty of Architecture Engineering Validated from Loughborough University - UK

#### PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

Udacity Cross-Skilling Track (React.Js)

December, 2022

Studied: JSX, Hooks, Functional Components, Routes.

Udacity Professional Front-End Development (Nano-Degree) November, 2022

Studied: JavaScript, ES6, Web API, Node.js, Agile.

Udacity Foundational Web Development (Nano-Degree) Se

September,2022

Studied: HTML, CSS, Basics of WordPress.

### **PROJECTS**

# E-Commerce Web application (React-Redux)

September, 2022

- Built e-commerce application with reusable components using React and Redux-Toolkit.
- https://github.com/omarmreda/E-commerce

### My Reads Application (React.js)

December, 2022

- Built a web application using functional components, Hooks and Routes.
- The user can Search for a book and put it on a shelf (Read, Currently Reading, want to Read).
- https://github.com/omarmreda/myreads

# Weather Journal Application (Vanilla JavaScript)

November, 2022

- Built local server with Node.Js and getting weather data from web API.
- <a href="https://github.com/omarmreda/Weather-Journal">https://github.com/omarmreda/Weather-Journal</a>

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# **Site Architect (Orbita for Contracting)**

October, 2020 - October, 2022

- Working as a Site Architect for retail projects.
- Finished 10 fast-track projects in 2 years.
- Working with sub-contractors on implementation of retail projects.

### **VOLUNTEERING**

## **AIESEC Cairo (Incoming Global Entrepreneur Team leader)**

2017 - 2018

 Helping 100+people from different counties to get internships and volunteering projects